CHLOE JEFFERSON

317-517-4135 | chloe.m.jefferson@gmail.com | Indianapolis, IN

SUMMARY

I am an experienced food safety and quality management professional and am currently a part-time remote student in software development. My background in areas such as quality assurance, regulatory affairs, R&D, data analysis, program management, customer relations, and biosecurity can be directly applied to a variety of professional roles. I have experience in fast-paced, highly regulated environments and dedicate the effort to learn new systems quickly.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Animal Sciences – Purdue University – West Lafayette, IN

May 2016

Yonsei International Summer School - South Korea

May - August 2016

- Engaged in international business coursework and cultural exchange at one of the top universities in the nation

Animals & Food Security: An International Service-Learning Experience (Heifer International) – Romania

May 2015

- Gained hands-on farm animal husbandry experience, insight on differences between the E.U. and U.S agriculture, and Purdue Extension exposure by creating resources to present farm best practices to community members with local DVM students

Software Development – Eleven Fifty Academy – Indianapolis, IN

November 2020 - Current

- 24-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training in C# and HTML/CSS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FSQR Superintendent – Cargill Protein – Fort Worth, TX (Food Safety, Quality, and Regulatory) – Albert Lea, MN

March 2019 - November 2019 May 2018 - March 2019

- Created, validated and verified programs in the food safety and quality management system for dual-regulated (FDA/USDA) and GFSI certified (BRC/SQF) human and pet food facilities by developing collaborative partnerships at all levels
 - o <u>Extensive Experience</u>: HACCP, Pathogen Control, Allergen, Foreign Material, Sanitation, Hygiene, and Defense Programs
- Compiled, analyzed, and presented FSQR-related KPI metrics, industry trends, and project statuses for the leadership team to assess the health of the facility and adjust strategies to meet business objectives
- Directed CAPA/incident responses for complaints, program deviations, regulatory non-conformities, and emergencies through communication with cross-functional teams, suppliers, contractors, customers, and regulatory authorities
- Coordinated implementation of standards, certification body transition, and non-compliance response for customer,
 regulatory, GFSI, and internal audits with facility leadership and corporate to successfully pass each audit
- Led department compliance with data reporting quality initiatives for Salesforce, Lab Helix (LIMS), PowerBI, Access, etc.
- Assisted with R&D/commercialization projects to investigate process capabilities, test new products, and update equipment
- Managed career development of two FSQR Supervisors and an FSQR Professional with ongoing performance reviews
- Oversaw product hold, pre-shipment review, release and COA reporting (chemistry, micro, and quality metrics)
- Audited sister facilities to identify opportunities and strengths while building relationships to share best practices

FSQR Data Analyst - Cargill Protein — Albert Lea, MN

October 2017 - May 2018

- Led department PI System implementation by troubleshooting with 3rd party programmers, training department on use of new tools, communicating program progress to management and corporate teams and generating reporting tools
- Analyzed trends in food safety and quality data to track compliance and support a culture of continuous improvement
- Trained to finalize status as a Cargill Food Safety Policy Manual Auditor by performing internal and supplier audits; assisting with facility audit preparation and response; and managing the facility internal housekeeping audit program
- Worked on multidisciplinary teams: Tare Weight Policy, Process Mapping, Food Safety, HAZMAT and Cargill Ebony Council
- Cross-trained to serve as backup for FSQR Techs, Supervisors, Document/Food Safety Specialists, and Superintendent

FSQR Supervisor - Cargill Protein - Albert Lea, MN

May - October 2017

- Headed food safety, quality, and regulatory communication and decision-making for 2nd and 3rd shifts in the facility
- Directed work of FSQR technicians; investigated incidents; conducted food safety and quality improvement projects; assisted with management of the listeria environmental monitoring program; and monitored basic chemistry and micro lab tasks
- Completed the Virtual Food Safety Auditor Academy training as a step toward becoming an internal and supplier auditor
- Served on the Food Safety Team, HAZMAT Team as a Qualified Technician, and the Cargill Ebony Council as Secretary
- Acquired knowledge of broader business functions during a seminar with marketing and R&D at the corporate headquarters

Operations/FSQR Associate – Cargill Protein – Nebraska City, NE

August 2016 - May 2017

- Performed labor yield study for accounting—documenting more than 500 individual product runs to help continuously
 improve operations by identifying opportunities and constraints and creating excel charts to report trends and variation
- Reported quality metrics using real-time data after being selected as Raw Operations Super User for Helix monitoring
- Served as an active member and contributor on BRC Prep Team, Safety (BBS) Team, Customer Response Team, Engagement Team, and an FMEA to support organizational goals
- Verified and updated Nutritional Facts Panel, Green Weight, Protein Fat-Free, and Environmental Monitoring programs
- Assisted R&D scientists on first production runs, new formulation tests, and a continuous improvement study
- Helped management with Spanish translation, work order preparation, and daily payroll tracking

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Minorities in Agriculture, Natural Resources, and Related Sciences (MANRRS)

2013 - 2019

- Professional Member: Recruited talent and strengthened chapter partnerships with the Cargill Ebony Council at conferences
- MANRRS-Purdue Chapter Executive Board: Coordinated events, meetings, fundraisers, travel, volunteering, and outreach

BestPrep Cloud Coach Mentor

2018, 2019

- Remotely mentored high school students on topics including career development, goal-setting, and personal branding

LEADERSHIP Albert Lea-Freeborn County - Freeborn County, MN

2017 - 2018

- Selected to engage in a community leadership program led by the Chamber of Commerce and Riverland Community College